Here's the easy way to create Lawn AI video. In this tutorial, I'm showing you exactly how I generated this realistic 44-second Lawn Pightsy,
and how I made this 71-second Lawn Shortroom, and now show you how to extend them even more to be as long as you want.
This is by far the simplest and easiest method to generate Lawn AI videos.
The first step is to use AI to generate a storyboard just like this one.
It's going to divide our Lawn AI videos into these separate scenes.
The tool we're going to use for this is the newest GPT-2 Image Model.
What this tool is amazing at is reasoning and generating text, and that's going to come in really handy for us
when we're trying to generate these Lawn Storyboards.
To use GPT Image2, I'm inside Higgs Field AI, and you can find it on the homepage,
or we can go to the list of Image Generators, and find the new GPT Image2 model.
For the first example I'm creating, I'm going to generate a Lawn AI video based around these two photos
of the scientists in the hazmat suit and his robot companion who are exploring this toxic forest.
So we have the GPT Image2 model chosen, and what I'm going to do is upload those two
reference images of my characters. Let's put those inside here.
Next, I'm going to ask the GPT Image2 model to create a full storyboard for us.
The prompt can be super, super simple.
Just a one sentence description is going to be enough to create a full storyboard.
Now, you have some other options like choosing the quality, the resolution of the storyboard,
and also the aspect ratio. I'll recommend setting this to 16 to 9.
And then we just have to generate the AI storyboard.
This is the full built out story. It's got 12 complete shots in it that tell a full story,
and underneath each individual shot there's a small text description.
Those little text descriptions are going to be super useful later on because we're going to use
those as part of the prompts for our AI video generator. I didn't notice sometimes that when
you're generating a bunch of separate panels like this, there is some repetition.
So if you look at this image in panel three, which is the robot gesturing upwards,
it ends up being the same image as shown inside panel 11.
So we need to make a minor edit to the storyboard so we don't have this repetition.
So inside Hicksfield, what I'm going to do is hit reference, which is going to let me edit this
storyboard. And so there's that storyboard added on into our image references. Let's delete all the
otherwise. And also change the prompt. What we want to do is change panel 11 so that it's not a
repetition of panel three. And that's basically exactly what I'm going to tell the AI to do.
Just adjust shot 11 so it's not a repeat of shot number three. And looking at the result,
it's swapped shot 11 to one of the scientists inspecting some kind of a toolkit.
So now that we have the storyboard sequence, how do we leverage this and turn it into a lawn AI
video? We're going to use a AI video model called cdance 2.0. So if we have a storyboard
and what cdance can do for us is to animate all of these in a single video generation at the same
time to use the cdance video model. I'm going to look through the video models on Hicksfield and
the top one is cdance 2.0. So for this AI video model, the maximum duration of each video generation
happens to be 15 seconds. So then how do we create a super lawn AI video sequence of our entire
storyboard? Well, if we try to fit this entire storyboard all 12 shots into a single 15 second video,
there just isn't enough time inside those 15 seconds to animate this entire storyboard. So I'm
going to split the storyboard up and crop out each individual role. So this is the first row
I've cropped out where I'm just taking the first four shots of that storyboard. And what we're
going to do is animate these four shots inside the 15 second video sequence and it should be able
to produce a pretty good result for us. A quick technical point you will need to layer the crop
role on top of a 16 by 9 image. This is just to make sure that Hicksfield can actually use this
image as a reference. For the prompt that I'm going to use, what I'm going to rely on is the
pre-generated text descriptions that's already inside the storyboard. So what we're going to do is
tell it to generate a scene using the shots in the uploaded film storyboard. Then for each of the
shots inside this 15 second video generation, I'm going to give it a time frame of when I want
the shot to happen. For example, the first four seconds and then for the description of what happens
in the shot, I'm basically just going to copy the text description that's already described in
the storyboard. And I'm going to fill out the rest of the prompt using the same method.
You'll also want to add in this line at the bottom that says no music and no subtitles.
I found that that just makes it much easier later on when we're putting everything together.
Before we go and use this prompt though, there's an really important addition that we need to add
into this to preserve character consistency. So if we just used the prompt exactly written like this,
we'll get results like this, which does basically animate the scene as expected, except the robot
doesn't look quite the same. For starters, in this sequence, the robot's legs look super long
for some reason. He should be much shorter than that. And there's a lot of different variation
in the way that the character looks between different video generations. We need an additional
character reference sheet so that when we generate the Launei video sequence of them,
they actually stay consistent throughout the entire scene. To create a character reference sheet,
I'm still going to use the GPT image 2 model. And I'm going to upload the original shot of my robot
in the forest. And then in the prompt, I'm going to tell it to create a character reference sheet.
I'm going to put the prompt in the description so you can go and copy it. And the prompt is going to
give us this really useful character reference sheet to help us maintain consistency inside the videos.
Now that we have all of these different assets, we can start putting together our Launei video
sequence. So first off, I'm going to upload into Higgs field. The first four shots of our
store board, along with the character reference sheet of our robot. Let's drag that inside there.
And inside the prompt, we're going to write it exactly like I previously described. So first
telling it to generate a scene using the shots inside the uploaded film store board. And here,
I'm actually going to make a reference to the film storyboard uploaded image. So type at,
which lets me tag different references. And then I'm going to write out each of the individual
scenes, just basically copy in the text descriptions already in the store board. And then inside this
prompt, I'm also going to need to reference our character sheet for the robot as well. So that the
AI video knows exactly what the robot should look like. So here, I'll add an additional tag
next to the word robot for our character sheet. I'm actually also going to do this
in a few other places as well. And then in the settings, I'm just going to make sure that I'm using
the full 15 second video duration. Now let's generate the video and see what it looks like.
That actually looks like it animated five shots here instead of the four shots that are
prompted for. But that's not a bad problem to have. It still followed all the shots inside the
store board accurately. And the robot looks great. And then using the same exact method, I went ahead
and animated the rest of the store board. So here's the animation sequence for role number two
of the store board, which is shots five through eight. And here are the last four shots of the store board.
And now we have three separate 15 second video clips that are in sequence to each other,
which means that we can combine them together into a full 45 second AI video sequence. But it
doesn't stop here. We can actually extend our store board as many times as we want to. So looking
at the sequence of shots inside the store board, what if we wanted to extend this so that they
start exploring the forest even more. What we can do is actually use GPT image two to generate the
next 12 panels of the store board as well. So here's what we're going to do inside the GPT two image
generator. We're going to upload the original store board reference. So this is the first 12 shots
that we just animated. And then I'm just going to upload a character reference sheet for my scientist
and also the character reference sheet that I generated for the robot. Then inside the problem,
I'm going to ask it to simply generate the next 12 panels of the store board. And here's a prompt
I'm going to use generate the next page of the store board from image one, which continues the
story with 12 panels using the uploaded images. The robot reveals hitting knowledge of the forest,
guiding the scientists to a deeper, more dangerous core where the source of the toxic outbreak lies.
And this is the extended store board that GPT image two has created for us. And then I can use
the same exact technique of animating four separate shots at the same time to turn this store board
into three 15 second video generations as well. And if you do the math using the two store board
pages will end up with six 15 second video clips, which is a 90 second video sequence.
I found that some of the sequences that I generated were a little bit repetitive.
So I ended up trimming it down to a 71 second video instead. But you can use this method
and extend your videos for as long as you want. I'm going to put a link in the description for
Higgsio AI. If you want to go and generate your own long video sequences using GPT image two
and cdance 2.0. Now one of the challenges we're going to run into this especially when animating
more dynamic action-packed scenes. For example, this fight scene that I created is that because of
how much action there is, I found that if we animate each of the rows inside the store board
separately and by themselves, it's much harder to combine them together seamlessly. So let's see
how we can fix this problem. First off, for my fight scene, these are the characters
ending environment that I want them to be in and this is the store board and the prompt that I
used inside GPT image two to create this. Now when I go and animate each row separately of the
store board, each of the individual animations look really really good. So this is the first row
animated and keep an eye on what happens in the last scene. The bounty hunter suddenly ambushes
the female character and has her in this chokehold. Now when I go and animate the second row of the
store board, it starts off with the first frame of them already engaged inside a fight scene.
If we look at this individually, it's a really amazing looking AI video. However, if we try to combine
those two separate 15 second clips together, the transition is going to look a little weird. So
starting with the first video sequence and suddenly jumping into the second video sequence.
That transition right there, it doesn't really make sense to use in the chokehold and suddenly
is free and engaged in a fight scene. So then how do we get the transitions to be seamless
inside our lawn AI video? What we're going to need to do is give the AI some extra information
when generating each individual video clip. So first, I'm going to use this tool called
Video Frame Extractor and I'm going to save that last image frame of our video sequence.
Now when we go and generate the next four shots of our store board sequence,
actually tell the AI to use the screenshot I just saved as the first frame and generate those
next four shots starting from that initial screenshot. This is what it's going to look like inside.
Hixield first with all of our image references uploaded and then inside the prompt, I'm going to
tell it to generate a scene using the uploaded film store board fight sequence. Starting with this
image frame of the female character getting attacked and then the rest of the prompt is written
just like how it was done before basically describing what happens inside each store board sequence.
Now when we go and generate this scene, it should generate the next four shots starting with
the initial image frames and using this method, you can generate endless continuous shots for your AI
films. Here's a quick note about using Hixfield when you upload image references. What Hixfield is
going to do is check the eligibility of each image. This is to avoid any copyright issues.
Now if you're using like a celebrity or a scene from a movie or something, it's going to get denied,
but sometimes when you upload images of your own characters as well, it can also get denied. So
the first time that I tried to upload my reference sheet from my bounty hunter character,
it actually got determined as not eligible. But then when I tried again, the next time it was
determined as eligible to be used. So if you try to do this and you upload an image of yourself
for your characters and it gets denied, just try uploading that image reference a few different
times and eventually it might work. Let's take a look at what the full animated
side scene looks like so you can get an idea of what this method is capable of.
If you also want a complete breakdown of 10 practical tips to generate the most realistic possible
AI views, go watch this guide right here.